Finding Aid for Kennedy family papers, 1860s-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Kennedy family papers 1860s-1982
Kennedy family.
3 linear feet
851693 Aa 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan family; papers, 1904-1928, of James A. Kennedy, Sr., Presbyterian clergyman; papers, 1925-1969, of James A. Kennedy, Jr., Ann Arbor, Michigan attorney, largely concerning organizational activities; and papers of Mrs. James A. Kennedy (nee Elizabeth Earhart), 1950-1956, concerning her activities in Ann Arbor civic and social organizations and miscellaneous Earhart family materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. James A. Kennedy, Jr. (donor no. 5028 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
James A. Kennedy, Sr. was a Presbyterian clergyman. His son, James A. Kennedy, Jr. was an Ann Arbor, Michigan attorney and civic leader. Elizabeth Earhart Kennedy (Mrs. James A. Kennedy, Jr.) was active in various Ann Arbor civic and social organizations.
The collection has been arranged into three series: James A. Kennedy, Sr.; James A. Kennedy, Jr.; and Elizabeth Earhart Kennedy. The correspondence of James A. Kennedy Jr. includes letters from Charles H. Cooley, 1926, Edward H. Litchfield, 1938, Chase S. Osborn, 1926-1927 and 1937, and James K. Pollock, 1938. His papers also detail his work with such organizations as the Ann Arbor Rotary, the First Presbyterian Church of Ann Arbor, the Michigan League for Planned Parenthood, the Michigan Merit System Association, the Michigan Civil Service Commission, the Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce, and the local Republican Party. The papers of Elizabeth Kennedy detail her work with the Ann Arbor Council of Social Agencies and the Community Chest, and other organizations. The photographs in the Elizabeth Kennedy series date back to the mid-nineteenth century and are of the Kennedy, Beal, and Stockdale families.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor Rotary Club.; Birth control.; Clergy--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Erhardt family.; First Presbyterian Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Kennedy family.; Michigan. Civil Service Commission.; Michigan League for Planned Parenthood.; Michigan Merit System Association.; Presbyterian Church--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Republican Party (Mich.); Zetema (Society: Detroit, Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Beal family.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ypsilanti.; Families.; Stockdale family.; Women.; Ypsilanti (Mich.)--Dwellings.
Contributors:
Cooley, Charles Horton, 1864-1929.; Kennedy, Elizabeth Earhart, 1909-; Kennedy, James Alexander, 1897-1969.; Litchfield, Edward H. (Edward Harold), 1914-1968.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968
Genre Terms:
Albums.; Photographs.; Tintypes.
- James A. Kennedy, Sr.
  - Papers 1914-1928 (Box 1)
  - Sermon materials 1904-1926 (Box 1)
- James A. Kennedy, Jr.
  - Correspondence
    - 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    - 1931-1935 (Box 1)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 1)
    - 1938-1940 (Box 1)
    - 1942 (Box 1)
    - 1951-1960 (Box 1)
    - 1961-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Organizational activities
    - Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce (Box 1)
      - General (Box 1)
      - Ann Arbor Development Council (Box 1)
      - Central Business District (Box 1)
        - 1959-1960 (Box 1)
        - 1961-1963 (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Citizens Council (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor First Presbyterian Church circa 1961 (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Rotary Club
      - Undated (Box 1)
      - 1947-1948 (Box 1)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 1)
      - 1951-1953 (Box 1)
      - 1952 April 20-21 Annual Conference (Box 1)
      - 1953 March 22-23 Annual Conference (Box 1)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 1)
      - 1956-1961 (Box 1)
      - Financial (Box 1)
      - History of 1916-1947 (Box 1)
      - Programs
        - 1947-1955 (Box 1)
        - 1956-1960 (Box 1)
    - Barton Hills (Ann Arbor), Abstract of the Title of (Box 2)
    - Civil Service Commission (Box 2)
    - Michigan League for Planned Parenthood (Box 2)
    - Huron Clinton Parkway Committee (Box 2)
    - Ann Arbor Committee on Municipal Government (Box 2)
    - Political Activities (Box 2)
    - Republican Party (Box 2)
- Elizabeth Earhart Kennedy
  - Correspondence 1925-1926 (Box 2)
  - Organizational Activities
    - Ann Arbor Y.M.C.A. 1953, undated (Box 2)
    - Ann Arbor Council of Social Agencies 1953-1956 Board of Directors (Box 2)
    - Ann Arbor Council of Social Agencies 1953, 1956, undated, Group work and recreation division (Box 2)
    - Ann Arbor Council of Social Agencies and the Community Chest
      - 1945-1950 (Box 2)
      - 1951-1967 (Box 2)
      - Undated (Box 2)
      - Annual Report 1952, 1953, 1955 (Box 2)
      - Printed (Box 2)
  - Personal and family materials used in the preparation of her book Coombs, Stockdales, Beals and the Great Migration (Ann Arbor 1983) (Box 3)
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Pattenden, Dorothy, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Pullan, Doris, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Williams, Elizabeth Stephenson (Box 3)
    - Family Materials
      - Anscomb family (Box 3)
      - Beal family (George) (Box 3)
      - Beal family (William) (Box 3)
      - Coombs family (Box 3)
      - Hargrove family (Box 3)
      - Neal family (Box 3)
      - Stephenson family (Box 3)
      - Stockdale family, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Photograph Album (Box 3)
    - Photographs (Box 3)
    - Remembrance Book (Box 3)
    - Zetema materials (Box 3)
    - Miscellanea 1917-1925 (Box 3)
      also includes Earhart family material